From the timeless beauty of the Taj Mahal to the mystery of Stonehenge, these wonders tell the story of humanity’s creativity and spirit.
از زیبایی جاودان تاج محل تا راز استون‌هنج، این شگفتی‌ها داستان خلاقیت و روح انسان را روایت می‌کنند.
In India, the Taj Mahal reflects love carved in marble.
در هند، تاج محل بازتاب عشقی است که بر سنگ مرمر حک شده است.
Across the mountains of northern China, the Great Wall stretches endlessly, a symbol of determination.
در کوه‌های شمال چین، دیوار بزرگ بی‌پایان کشیده شده؛ نمادی از اراده و پایداری.
In Jordan, the ancient city of Petra was carved into rose-colored stone.
در اردن، شهر باستانی پترا در دل سنگ‌های سرخ تراشیده شده است.
The Parthenon of Greece stands as a tribute to art, logic, and balance.
پارتنون یونان نمادی از هنر، منطق و توازن است.
Rome’s Colosseum still holds the echo of ancient crowds.
کولوسئوم رم هنوز پژواک جمعیت دوران باستان را در خود دارد.
The Pyramids of Giza in Egypt remain a testament to human engineering and faith.
اهرام جیزه در مصر گواهی از مهندسی و ایمان انسان هستند.
High in the Andes, Machu Picchu rises above the clouds, a harmony of stone and sky.
در کوه‌های آند، ماچو پیچو بالاتر از ابرها برمی‌خیزد؛ هماهنگی میان سنگ و آسمان.
In Mexico, the Chichén Itzá pyramid unites science and architecture under the sun.
در مکزیک، هرم چیچن ایتزا علم و معماری را زیر خورشید به هم پیوند می‌دهد.
The sacred Angkor Wat in Cambodia tells stories of gods and kings through its walls.
انگکور وات مقدس در کامبوج داستان خدایان و پادشاهان را بر دیوارهایش حک کرده است.
And in England, the ancient stones of Stonehenge remind us of the mystery that connects us all.
و در انگلستان، سنگ‌های باستانی استون‌هنج یادآور رازی است که همه ما را به هم پیوند می‌دهد.
These monuments are not just places — they are chapters of our shared story.
این بناها فقط مکان نیستند — آن‌ها فصل‌هایی از داستان مشترک ما هستند.